Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
All right, welcome back to the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship study group.
好的，欢迎回到以太坊协议研究小组。
This is week six and the start of the distributed tracks here.
这是第六周，这是分布式轨道的开始。
So today we will be starting the development track with Xiaowei and Sam,
因此，今天我们将与Xiaowei和Sam一起开始开发轨道
creators and masters of the specs from the consensus layer and the execution layer.
从共识层和执行层的规格的创建者和主人。
So yeah, I think we'll probably get started with xiaowei first.
是的，我认为我们可能会首先开始使用Xiaowei。
Mario, maybe you want to give xiaowei a quick introduction?
马里奥，也许您想给木夫快速介绍吗？
Yeah, for sure.
是的，肯定。
Yeah, so again, welcome everyone in the week six of our, in the second phase of our program.
是的，再次，在我们计划的第二阶段中，在我们第六周的第六周欢迎所有人。
We will have another talk on research domain on Wednesday, but today's Monday and we have
我们将在周三关于研究领域的另一个谈话，但今天的星期一，我们有
development track and uh very important topic that i believe that ethereum developers need to be
我认为以太坊开发人员需要成为的开发轨道和非常重要的话题
familiar with and uh these are specifications so the consensus and the execution layer specification
熟悉和uh这些是规格，因此共识和执行层规范
uh and we are lucky enough to have basically creators of these specifications in python
嗯，我们很幸运地在Python中基本上拥有这些规格的创建者
here today xiaowei and sam and um one one important note to start with these are like
今天在这里xiaowei和sam and um，一首重要的便条开始就是
two distinct projects like they they kind of evolved separately and the consensus layer
两个不同的项目，例如他们分开演变，共识层
it's the specs are older one or the python version is the uh what what came first uh because xiaowei
这是规格较早的规格，或者python版本是uh，因为xiaowei是什么
have been working on uh the research team uh correct me if i'm wrong since like 2017 i think
如果我想像2017年，我认为我纠正了我的研究团队，我认为我纠正了我
um basically creating um the design of the beacon chain itself way before it uh it launched uh
嗯，基本上创建了信标链本身的设计，然后它推出了uh
before the merge and everything so she's been with us for for many years now and uh yeah it's
在合并之前和一切之前，她已经和我们在一起已经呆了很多年了，是的
an honor to have you here uh we will learn about the the technical side of the specs uh and i
很荣幸能在这里有您的荣幸，我们将了解规格的技术方面
believe it shall we uh so uh we we have this call a bit earlier than normally because she's in the
相信我们应该这样做，所以我们的电话比往常早一点，因为她在
east asia and i believe that she's also hoping to have some maybe new colleagues or some new
东亚和我相信她也希望有一些新的同事或一些新的同事
ethereum developers from from asia so i hope that uh our protocol fellowship follows here
以太坊开发人员来自亚洲
uh get inspired yeah uh yeah xiaowei it's uh the stage is yours please go ahead
嗯，受到启发是的，是的，xiaowei是你的舞台是你
thank you mario for the present um introduction let me share my screen just now
谢谢Mario的目前介绍，让我现在分享我的屏幕
it's pretty much it's pretty much it's pretty much it's pretty much it's pretty much it's pretty much
几乎这几乎是它几乎是它的几乎是
So it is totally open source, it's the most Ethereum core project.
因此，它是完全开源的，它是最以太坊的核心项目。
We have more than 100 contributors now.
我们现在有100多个贡献者。
I think most of them are core devs that really need and use this space.
我认为其中大多数是真正需要并使用此空间的核心开发人员。
And the license is totally it's CC0 open source Python project.
许可证完全是CC0开源Python项目。
So you can, if you see it on the GitHub category, then it is a Python project.
因此，您可以，如果您在GitHub类别上看到它，那就是一个Python项目。
Yes.
是的。
Okay, so you can use this link to see what it is, what it looks like.
好的，因此您可以使用此链接来查看它是什么，外观。
So for the Python spec, the CL spec,
因此，对于Python规范，CL规格，
it has three purposes here.
它在这里有三个目的。
So first, the most thing is,
因此，首先，最多的是
the most important thing is it's the center
最重要的是是中心
of the Ethereum core consensus applications,
以太坊核心共识应用程序的
which means it defines the protocol in the files.
这意味着它在文件中定义了协议。
it's the most interesting part is it is executable and verifiable it can be filled into a python
最有趣的部分是它可以执行和可验证，可以填充到python中
program and then can be executed we will talk about it in details later and third it's also
程序然后可以执行我们将在稍后详细讨论，第三，也是
interesting is it is also the test vector generator for the CLKinds to test their implementations.
有趣的是，它也是Crkinds测试其实现的测试向量生成器。
All right, so whenever we want to add a new features, like a new patch to the current
好的，因此，每当我们想添加新功能，例如当前的新补丁
main net protocol, we will open,
主要净协议，我们将打开，
create a new feature markdown file in the space.
在空间中创建一个新功能标记文件。
And we will write it in markdown file.
我们将将其写入Markdown文件。
For example, the last half work it was the
例如，最后一部分是
then app half work.
然后应用半工作。
So we are going to include like, for example,
因此，我们将包括，例如
like EIP 6110, and then there'll be a file
像EIP 6110，然后有一个文件
a folder called ip6110 and some files in it right so and the second um we will release the new
一个称为IP6110的文件夹，其中一些文件正确，第二个文件，第二个文件，我们将发布新的文件
pi spec with test vectors uh suits that so the test vectors would be generated with the pi high
带有测试向量的Pi Spec UH西装，因此可以使用PI高生成测试向量
High-Spec Program Test Cases for Clientings to verify.
高规格的程序测试用例，用于验证的客户案例。
And all this is an important and unique component
所有这些都是重要而独特的组成部分
of the current CLRMD process.
当前的CLRMD过程。
It helps us to found the basic box
它可以帮助我们找到基本框
before clientings implement,
在客户实施之前，
because at the stage of writing the spec,
因为在编写规范的阶段，
we can test it.
我们可以测试。
the clienting program will be, I mean,
我的意思是，客户计划将是
they can also use it to double verify it.
他们还可以使用它来验证它。
So it's pretty helpful tool for the ecosystem.
因此，这对于生态系统是非常有用的工具。
So, so I think people would be wonder that
所以，我认为人们会想知道
why we use Python.
为什么我们使用Python。
So, so I think it is because the Python
所以，我认为这是因为Python
Because Python is one of the most readable language for developers.
因为Python是开发人员最可读的语言之一。
Because most pseudo-codes look like Python.
因为大多数伪代码看起来都像Python。
We also try to write the spec code in the simplest way, instead of using some fancy,
我们还尝试以最简单的方式编写规格代码，而不是使用一些幻想，
efficient Python magic.
有效的Python魔术。
we do care about the readability and simplification first.
首先，我们确实关心可读性和简化。
So if you want to read it to understand one of the features and how you can browse it,
因此，如果您想阅读它以了解其中一个功能以及如何浏览它，
So if you have the repository URL on your laptop, you can take a look that under the
因此，如果您的笔记本电脑上的存储库URL，则可以看一看
Specs folder, there are the main net hard forks, for example, like the
规格文件夹，例如，有主要网叉
Altaire, Beatrix, Capella, and Dennett.
Altaire，Beatrix，Capella和Dennett。
Those are the half of already happened
那是已经发生的一半
and launched on the main net.
并在主网上发射。
And inside the features folder,
在功能文件夹中，
you can see some work in progress research project in it.
您可以看到其中的一些正在进行的研究项目。
And so for example,
例如，
if you want to read the base zero space,
如果要读取零基本空间，
you can see there are different Markdown files in it.
您可以看到其中有不同的标记文件。
And the beacon-chain-markdown.nd
和信标链痕迹
is the entry of the beacon-chain consensus.
是信标链共识的进入。
So I would recommend if you want to read it,
因此，我建议您要阅读，
it starts from this file.
它从这个文件开始。
And there are also other different components for the CL.
CL还有其他不同的组件。
For example, like folk choice,
例如，像民间选择一样
we defined the folk choice logic in this file.
我们在此文件中定义了民间选择逻辑。
And about the networking it is in the P2P interface
关于网络，它在P2P接口中
markdown file.
标记文件。
Yup.
是的。
And also for the future different folks,
以及未来的不同人
it could be more different component
它可能是更多不同的组件
that we will add in the future.
我们将来会添加。
Okay, so if you started to read it, you can start with the type and value definitions.
好的，因此，如果您开始阅读它，则可以从类型和值定义开始。
We define the, you can see that we define the constants and some configurations, values
我们定义了，您可以看到我们定义了常数和一些配置，值
in the Markdown tables like this.
在这样的降价表中。
So like, what's it at?
所以，这是什么？
The name of this basic custom type
此基本自定义类型的名称
and what is it's SSE equivalent
和什么是SSE等效的
and also like some description.
也喜欢一些描述。
And beside that, you can see in the,
除此之外，您可以在
we have the preset and configuration.
我们有预设和配置。
They are basically like the configuration that we set,
它们基本上就像我们设置的配置一样
that we set but we will manage them in different ways so the values are defined in this markdown
我们设置了，但我们将以不同的方式管理它们，以便在此标记中定义值
tables um and then you can also see we have defined the xyz containers in this markdown file
表UM，然后您也可以看到我们在此Markdown文件中定义了XYZ容器
the for example there's a beacon black body and the beacon block and the beacon black would use
例如，有一个灯塔黑色的身体和灯塔块，而Beacon Black会使用
it can become black body.
它可以变成黑色身体。
In, I can see in the last field it is body.
在，我可以在最后一个领域看到它是身体。
Yeah, so the classes are the SSE containers.
是的，所以课程是SSE容器。
It is also the serialization schema
它也是序列化模式
for the consensus objects.
对于共识对象。
Yeah, so if you want to understand more about SSE,
是的，因此，如果您想了解更多有关SSE的信息，
you can also find the documents in the same repository.
您还可以在同一存储库中找到文档。
Yeah, here.
是的，在这里。
And okay.
好的。
So it could write Python function in code block
因此它可以在代码块中写入Python函数
to describe the consensus rule.
描述共识规则。
Can see this is an example of the entry
可以看到这是条目的示例
of the state transition functions.
状态过渡功能。
We, there are some assertions
我们，有一些断言
for example like assert verify block signature like um so it is the this condition that need
例如，像ostert验证块签名一样，是这样需要的
to be satisfied in the consensus rules so um if this condition is not satisfied it's all
要在共识规则中满足，所以如果不满足此条件，
it will store um exception oh that means the given input is considered as invalid input
它将存储UM例外OH，这意味着给定输入被视为无效输入
So you can use this assertion to see what the consensus verifications are.
因此，您可以使用此断言来查看共识验证是什么。
There are also some other valuable resources for you to learn the design and deeper rationales.
您还有其他一些宝贵的资源，可以学习设计和更深入的理由。
I think I would recommend two resources. One is Vitalik's annotated spike, and another
我想我会推荐两个资源。一个是Vitalik的注释尖峰，另一个是
one is Ben Edgerton's Upgrading Ethereum book.
一本是本·埃格顿（Ben Edgerton）升级的以太坊书籍。
Okay, so as I described, the spike's POC is, I mean, they are markdown files, but there's
好的，正如我所描述的
something, some magic inside it,
里面有一些魔术，
it's a pattern, I call it the, like the spec ELF,
这是一个模式，我称其为“规格精灵”，
like it basically, we do something in,
基本上，我们在做某事，
under it and it needs to,
在它之下，它需要，
to pass it the markdown file,
要将其传递给Markdown文件，
to pass the markdown file and convert
传递降价文件并转换
the markdown file content into a Python program.
将markdown文件内容变成python程序。
So this is the build spec,
所以这是构建规范，
it will do something that the reader shouldn't know indeed.
它将做一些读者确实不知道的事情。
So, for example, the Phase Zero beacon chain
因此，例如，零相信标链
The face zero will be passed to the spec builder, and it will become the face zero.
面部零将传递给规格构建器，它将变成零面。
Then for the next hard fork it's called Altair.
然后，对于下一个硬叉，称为Altair。
It is actually like an extent of the previous hard forks.
实际上，这就像以前的坚硬叉子一样。
So the Altair hard fork will use
因此Altair硬叉将使用
the previous hard fork first zeros content
以前的硬叉第一零内容
and then add some extra modification into it.
然后在其中添加一些额外的修改。
So it combines both files
因此，它结合了两个文件
and convert it into one single Altair beacon chain spike.
并将其转换为一个单一的Altair信标链钉。
And yeah, and the Bellatrix and the other following spikes
是的，贝拉特里克斯和其他以下尖峰
are doing the same thing similar.
正在做同样的事情。
Yeah, so, and last, we want to introduce
是的，所以，最后，我们想介绍
how to use PySpec, I mean it's a suitable program.
如何使用PYSPEC，我的意思是这是一个合适的程序。
So you can install it from the source code,
因此，您可以从源代码安装它，
code and run this make file commands easily to install the required testing packages and
代码并运行此制作文件命令以安装所需的测试包和
build the PySpec.
构建Pyspec。
So you can try to write your first PySpec program it is a hello world example you can
因此，您可以尝试编写您的第一个PYSPEC程序，这是一个Hello World示例，您可以
it's called the basic spike of the basic fork.
它称为基本叉的基本尖峰。
For in this example it is the Bellatrix fork.
因为在此示例中是贝拉特里克斯叉。
And then you can import the components,
然后您可以导入组件，
the containers of this spike.
这个尖峰的容器。
For example, this is the beacon black body
例如，这是Beacon Black Body
and there's a field called graffiti.
还有一个名为涂鸦的领域。
So it's some graffiti, like random string into it.
因此，这是一些涂鸦，例如随机字符串。
And the block itself it is an SSE object, and you can print it out to your screen and
块本身是一个SSE对象，您可以将其打印到屏幕上，并且
see it put the string hello world into the block.
看到它使弦hello世界进入街区。
And if you want to try something more interesting, you can also write your first PySpec test.
而且，如果您想尝试一些更有趣的东西，也可以编写第一个PYSPEC测试。
So this is what the one test case looks like.
这就是一个测试用例的样子。
So it's basically a pie test.
因此，这基本上是馅饼测试。
Test.
测试。
If you have written a pie test test,
如果您写了饼测试，
then it is simple.
然后很简单。
What we do here is to prepare the block.
我们在这里做的是准备块。
So this time, we build an empty block for the next step.
因此，这次，我们为下一步建造一个空块。
So, two inputs of this test cases, one is the spike, another is the Genesis state.
因此，该测试案例的两个输入，一个是尖峰，另一个是创世纪状态。
And after you write some test, you can also verify if the post state is correct as you
在写一些测试后，您还可以验证帖子状态是否正确
estimated it.
估计它。
So, you can write the assertion here.
因此，您可以在此处写断言。
in the last and so um in previous i talked about how to um it is the also it i mean the
在上一个和上一个中，我谈到了如何去，这也是我的意思是
isek is also the test generator so um actually we can reuse the pi test cases to generate the pi
ISEK也是测试生成器，因此实际上我们可以重复使用PI测试案例来生成PI
the test vectors and the magical part is here is that we yelled certain data out to um so if
测试向量和神奇的部分是我们向UM大喊某些数据，因此
i if i write your pre-state here it will output a file called pre that xz and it will be an encoded
我在这里写下您的预状态，它将输出一个名为pre the xz的文件，它将是一个编码
it will be encoded beacon state data in it.
它将在其中编码信标状态数据。
So in this case, we will yield one pre-state
因此，在这种情况下，我们将产生一个预状态
and the post-state, and then the series of blocks
以及后期，然后是一系列块
that we will put into the state transition function.
我们将投入到状态过渡功能中。
So, you know, the client can get through all of them
因此，您知道，客户可以通过所有这些
then they can verify it,
然后他们可以验证它，
that if their state transition function is correct.
如果他们的状态过渡功能正确。
Yup, oh, right, and like this.
是的，哦，对，这样。
This is the test vectors repository.
这是测试向量存储库。
So this is the example here, this are the output.
因此，这是这里的示例，这是输出。
Yeah, and if you are interested,
是的，如果您有兴趣，
can find some more details of how to run pySpec and what are the test formats look like
可以找到更多有关如何运行PYSPEC的详细信息，测试格式是什么样的
oh and if you are interested in helping the CL research and development
哦，如果您有兴趣帮助CL研发
I think pySpec is a pretty good simple start to learn and then you can go move to contribute
我认为PYSPEC是一个很好的开始学习的很好的开始，然后您可以去做贡献
So I think there are different levels that you can participate in.
因此，我认为您可以参与不同的级别。
So first you can look around and then maybe start with just a typo fix or like for the layout, anything you can do.
因此，首先，您可以环顾四周，然后只需使用错字修复即可开始，或者您可以做任何您可以做的事情。
um and the second is that you can probably help to refactor the code base
嗯，第二个是您可能可以帮助重构代码库
and then the level three is that you might you can try to hack some new age test cases
然后，第三级是您可能可以尝试破解一些新时代的测试用例
that we haven't covered yet i mean that would be really helpful to um the seal times
我们还没有覆盖，我的意思是真的很有帮助
and the fourth is that you can probably submit a bounty if you found the box in the sales day
第四是如果您在销售日找到盒子，您可能可以提交赏金
it comes right and thank you um this is the
这是对的，谢谢你，这是
it is my introduction of I say thank you and
这是我介绍我说谢谢，
Mario yeah thank you awesome thank you thank you so much our way yeah it was
马里奥是的，谢谢你真棒，谢谢你，非常感谢你的方式是的
it was awesome um really appreciate it um great intro a lot of a lot of information
真是太棒了，非常感谢它很棒的介绍很多信息
uh people are still care processing it maybe there will be some questions um
嗯，人们仍在关心处理它，也许会有一些问题
uh but yeah it's it's a really great um i
嗯，是的，这是一个很棒的嗯
yeah i want to uh want to maybe ask if you um if you can tell us maybe a bit about how uh
是的，我想问你是否可以问你是否可以告诉我们一些有关uh的信息
the consensus specs interact with the execution side?
共识规格与执行方进行交互？
For example, it was a question about the state transition function that you mentioned.
例如，这是关于您提到的状态过渡功能的问题。
Like, I suppose that
就像，我想
consensus layer updates the execution of the work choice.
共识层更新工作选择的执行。
But can you maybe elaborate more about the instruction there,
但是，您能否详细介绍那里的说明，
how the state transition happens on CL and it's mapped to the EL?
国家过渡是如何在CL上发生的，并映射到EL？
Yeah, okay, let me
是的，好，让我
Okay, we have to share another screen.
好的，我们必须共享另一个屏幕。
Okay, so this is the CL Specs index.
好的，这是CL规格索引。
So let's see the spec itself.
因此，让我们看看规格本身。
So here it is the state transition of the beacon chain.
因此，这是信标连锁店的状态过渡。
So beacon chain it will, we have the pre-state and the snipe beacon block here, and then
因此，信标连锁店将会在这里有预状态和狙击信标块，然后
we don't have um output here but the state itself it will be mother modified during the
我们在这里没有UM输出
state transition
国家过渡
so after um we process slot and block and the result state then object will be updated and about
因此，在UM之后，我们处理插槽和块以及结果状态，然后将对象进行更新以及有关
the relationship between it and the folk choice, you can take a look at the folk choice markdown
它与民间选择之间的关系，您可以看一下民间选择Markdown
file. So it's very interesting. So it it's about defines like what are the correct behavior that
文件。所以这很有趣。因此，它是定义的，就像什么是正确的行为
client should do when they receive a new block or a new attestation yeah and so for example if
客户在收到新的块或新证明时应做，例如
on the time that um upon the time they receiving a block they will call this implementation so the
在收到块的时间，他们将称此实现为
client have different information i mean information to make more um efficient execution
客户有不同的信息，我的意思是提供更有效的执行
But PySpec is like, we just want to define the rule clearly.
但是Pyspec就像，我们只想清楚地定义规则。
And I think we have called it state transition yes,
我认为我们称其为国家过渡是的，
inside the block function.
内部功能。
So upon they receive the site block,
因此，在他们收到现场块时，
they will do some verification for the folk choice.
他们将对民间选择进行一些验证。
And if it's okay,
如果可以的话，
then it will call the state transition here.
然后，它将在这里调用国家过渡。
Yeah, and then update the local database of the kind later.
是的，然后以后更新此类的本地数据库。
Yeah, I think.
是的，我想。
Yeah, did I answered your question?
是的，我回答了您的问题吗？
Yes, I believe it's pretty great.
是的，我相信这很棒。
Yeah, thanks so much.
是的，非常感谢。
I appreciate you going through the actual repo
感谢您通过实际的存储库
and showing us the dates.
并向我们​​展示日期。
This is really great, yeah.
是的，这真的很棒。
Yeah, we have maybe five more minutes.
是的，我们还有五分钟。
Let's see if there are any more questions.
让我们看看是否还有其他问题。
What about testing reorganization issues?
测试重组问题呢？
I suppose you mean chain reorgs?
我想你的意思是链条？
Yeah, whether there is some sort of testing for chain reorgs,
是的，是否对链条进行了某种测试，
whether how the consensus specs handle the orgs.
共识规格如何处理组织。
Right, so in the Casper FFG implementation,
是的，因此在Casper FFG实施中，
so actually the prokchoice is the Casper FFG
因此，实际上Prokchoice是Casper FFG
it's pretty deep.
很深。
We can go back a bit to see the store.
我们可以回去看商店。
So we defined an abstract data class here.
因此，我们在此处定义了一个抽象数据类。
These are the fields that we want
这些是我们想要的领域
to describe what are the fields that
描述哪些领域
could be used for handle the reorg and the state transition.
可用于处理reorg和状态过渡。
So you can see we have stored the justified checkpoint
因此，您可以看到我们存储了合理的检查点
of the local view, the current view of the client
在本地视图中，客户的当前视图
and the finalized checkpoint.
和最终检查点。
And there are some, I think it will be
还有一些，我认为会
some of the, maybe it's too detailed,
其中一些，也许太详细了，
is that the unrealized
那是未实现的
justified checkpoint, unrealized, finalized checkpoint.
合理的检查点，未实现的，最终确定的检查点。
So, and also the blocks and the state.
因此，以及街区和国家。
So the blocks are, it is actually a dictionary.
因此，块是，它实际上是一个字典。
So we use the root, the black root as the identifier.
因此，我们将根，黑根作为标识符。
And so the state shared,
因此，国家共享
the root is the black root,
根是黑根，
and then the content is the state of the given black root.
然后内容是给定黑根的状态。
So you can see, we have this kind of the fields.
因此，您可以看到，我们有这样的领域。
And then when we handle,
然后当我们处理时
where we handle the reorg,
我们处理reorg的地方，
it's pretty easy it's pretty easy
很容易，很容易
okay um
好吧，嗯
So this helper will update the checkpoints, it includes the justified checkpoints and
因此，此助手将更新检查点，其中包括合理的检查点和
finalized trick point and so you can see uh you can search this function inside the this document
最终的技巧点，因此您可以在本文档中看到uh uh搜索此功能
and you can see where we update the where we update the checkpoints so basically the currently
您可以看到我们更新在哪里更新检查点的位置，因此基本上是当前的
the the basic um stapled
基本的UM钉
state we will use um we will use the justified um checkpoint state as the basic stable state
状态我们将使用UM我们将使用合理的UM检查点状态作为基本稳定状态
but there's also the head of the
但是还有
the state so it will go through the
国家这样将通过
a series of LND ghost book choice anxiety implications.
一系列LND幽灵书选择焦虑的影响。
And then in some certain cases, we all might have.
然后，在某些情况下，我们所有人都可能有。
So this is one of the cases here.
因此，这是这里的一种情况。
So basically, you can follow the coding.
因此，基本上，您可以关注编码。
you can see how we describe the whole LND ghost in this book choice document.
您可以看到我们如何描述本书选择文档中的整个LND鬼。
Yeah, and if you have some more detailed questions, you can ask me in Discord or somewhere else.
是的，如果您有一些更详细的问题，可以在Discord或其他地方问我。
Thank you, Mario. Yeah, yeah, thank you, xiaowei. Yeah, it's awesome, it's amazing to see how you
谢谢，马里奥。是的，谢谢你，小韦。是的，太棒了，很高兴看到您如何
orient and explain the different parts it's it's it's it's it's really great appreciate it
东方并解释不同的部分是它真的很棒
and uh maybe one last question we have from sam here uh what's what was the biggest
呃，也许我们从山姆这里遇到的最后一个问题是什么是最大的
challenge you faced uh when developing the cdl specs what do you find most challenging
挑战您在开发CDL规格时面对UH的挑战您发现最具挑战性的是什么
um so hello good question the most challenging uh i think
嗯，你好，好问题，我认为最具挑战性的嗯
So performance, I think it would be the shared challenge for all the Python projects.
因此，性能，我认为这将是所有Python项目的共同挑战。
And the second thing for myself, maybe not for Phyllis, is that, as I say, that we have
对我自己的第二件事，也许不是菲利斯（Phyllis），正如我说的那样，我们有
to convert the markdown file into the Python program.
将Markdown文件转换为Python程序。
But so for the spec writer, you have two choices.
但是对于规格作者来说，您有两种选择。
One is that you can update the markdown file directly.
一个是您可以直接更新Markdown文件。
And then every time you want to verify it,
然后每次您想验证它，
you have to build it into the Python program.
您必须将其构建到Python程序中。
And then the second one is that you can probably write
然后第二个是你可以写
it on the Python program,
它在Python计划中
but eventually you will have to write it back
但是最终您将不得不写回去
to the markdown file.
到Markdown文件。
So I do feel it is a bit tiring if you have to do this conversion.
因此，如果您必须进行此转换，我确实觉得有点累。
But that's my word for now.
但这是我现在的话。
Yeah.
是的。
And yes, I hope I answered that question too.
是的，我希望我也回答了这个问题。
Yeah, yeah, of course.
是的，当然。
Yeah, thanks so much, Haowei.
是的，非常感谢，Haowei。
Yeah, it feels great.
是的，感觉很棒。
We are at half an hour.
我们正好半个小时。
And yeah,
是的，
really appreciate it.
真的很感激。
We have the Discord.
我们有不和谐。
I will share you the link
我会分享你的链接
so maybe there are some extra questions
所以也许还有一些额外的问题
you can answer there.
您可以在那里回答。
But it's been really great.
但这真的很棒。
I hope there might be some contributors
我希望可能有一些贡献者
to CLSpec or somebody
到Clspec或某人
who learned HighSpec from you.
谁从你那里学到了高音。
Yeah, I really appreciate it.
是的，我真的很感激。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
And especially thank you so much
特别感谢你
for staying up so late for us tonight
今晚为我们熬夜
or maybe too early.
也许太早了。
I'm not sure right now, but yeah, thanks so much, Shelley.
我现在不确定，但是，是的，非常感谢，雪莱。
Appreciate it so much.
非常感谢。
It was really great.
真的很棒。
Thank you, Mario.
谢谢，马里奥。
Yeah, and thank you, Josh.
是的，谢谢乔什。
And let's see, Sam.
让我们看看，山姆。
Looking forward to Sam's presentation.
期待山姆的演讲。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Yeah.
是的。
Bye-bye.
再见。
Sam, Mario, are you with us?
山姆，马里奥，你和我们在一起吗？
Thanks so much, Shelley.
非常感谢，雪莱。
Thank you so much again.
再次非常感谢。
Yeah, and Sam, if you are with us,
是的，山姆，如果你和我们在一起，
please join us on the stage.
请加入我们的舞台。
Can you hear us?
你能听到我们的声音吗？
I can.
我可以。
Awesome, awesome.
很棒，很棒。
Yeah.
是的。
So now we will move to the execution side of things with Sam here.
因此，现在我们将在这里与Sam一起转到执行方面。
And we are doing the execution second, because they are also kind of younger, these specs,
我们正在执行第二，因为它们也很年轻，这些规格，
because Sam has been working on these for, like, maybe the past three years or more.
因为山姆一直在为过去三年或更长时间以来的工作。
Correct me if I'm wrong.
如果我错了，请纠正我。
Yeah, about that.
是的，对此。
Yeah, Sam with his team, with all the other folks, have been developing the ELs, the executive
是的，山姆与他的团队以及其他所有人一起发展ELS，高管
execution layer specs uh which are uh similar to the pi spec you just saw um uh and uh sam
执行层规格uh uh类似于您刚刚看到的Pi规格
actually you might know him from different places around the ethereum he's also very active eip editor
实际上，您可能从以太坊周围的不同地方认识他，他也非常活跃的EIP编辑器
uh helping to maintain the whole eip echo with uh osmium software and also running the um uh the
UH帮助通过UH OSMIUM软件维护整个EIP回波，并运行UM UH
all wallets helping to help you to standardize and develop the Ethereum wallets around the ecosystem.
所有钱包都可以帮助您标准化和开发生态系统周围的以太坊钱包。
So it's really great to have you here, Sam. And yeah, we are eager to hear about the execution
山姆，把你带到这里真是太好了。是的，我们渴望听到执行
specs, it's a pretty set of things. So all right, let's see if my screen sharing works here.
规格，这是一组漂亮的东西。好吧，让我们看看我的屏幕共享在这里是否有效。
I want to share this one.
我想分享这个。
All right.
好的。
And let's make this.
让我们做这个。
There.
那里。
Can everybody see that?
每个人都可以看到吗？
Yeah, awesome.
是的，很棒。
Go ahead.
前进。
Perfect.
完美的。
All right.
好的。
So I'm here to talk about the Ethereum execution layer specification, or ELSE for short.
因此，我在这里谈论以太坊的执行层规范，或者简而言之。
I'd like to start off my presentations with a very quick summary.
我想通过一个非常快速的摘要开始演讲。
So if you're only going to watch 30 seconds of this presentation, these are the 30 seconds
因此，如果您只想观看此演示文稿的30秒，那么这些是30秒
you really want to see.
你真的想看。
So we started off with the yellow paper.
因此，我们从黄纸开始。
It's written like an academic paper.
它写得像学术论文。
It uses very dense mathematic notation.
它使用非常密集的数学符号。
A lot of non-English characters in there.
那里有很多非英语角色。
And kind of where we're going and where we are right now is a fully executable Python implementation of the Ethereum execution layer.
以及我们要去的地方以及现在的位置是以太坊执行层的完全可执行的Python实现。
These kind of pictures here just highlight, you know, exactly what we can do.
您知道，这里的这些图片只是突出显示我们能做什么。
So on the left here, you can see kind of a diff between the preceding fork and the subsequent fork.
因此，在这里的左侧，您可以看到前叉和后叉之间的差异。
And you can see all the differences there and kind of a similar thing on the right.
您可以看到那里的所有差异，并在右边看到类似的东西。
So this is what the specs looks like.
这就是规格的样子。
This is what we've built.
这就是我们建立的。
it's a regular Python program. That's it for the summary, a little bit about me. I'm Sam Wilson,
这是一个常规的Python程序。总结就是这样，关于我的一点。我是山姆·威尔逊，
I'm an EIP editor, I work on a bunch of projects, you can find me on GitHub or on Mastodon.
我是EIP编辑，我从事大量项目，您可以在Github或Mastodon上找到我。
So what is an Ethereum execution layer specification? Well it's a Python reference
那么什么是以太坊执行层规范？好吧，这是Python的参考
implementation of most of an Ethereum client. We do leave out some pretty important parts,
实施大多数以太坊客户端。我们确实忽略了一些非常重要的部分，
We don't do networking. We don't do fork choice. We don't do reorgs. But other than that, we pretty
我们不进行网络。我们不做叉子的选择。我们不这样做。但是除此之外，我们很漂亮
much built the entire executions layer. The other members of my team are Guru and Peter.
大量构建了整个执行层。我团队的其他成员是大师和彼得。
If you ever have any questions about the spec, you want to contribute, you can reach out to
如果您对规格有任何疑问，您想做出贡献，可以联系
myself or either of these two fine people, and we would be happy to help you.
我自己或这两个好人中的任何一个，我们很乐意为您提供帮助。
it. And just like the consensus layer specs, we've had contributors from everywhere, from
它。就像共识层规格一样，我们到处都有贡献者
all over the world. There's even a PO app if people like collecting those. So, yeah.
全世界。如果人们喜欢收集这些应用，甚至还有一个PO应用程序。所以，是的。
So big thank you to all these people. And yeah. A little bit of history now. So the
非常感谢所有这些人。是的。现在有一点历史。所以
Yellow Paper was created in 2014. It's a little bit more restrictive license. It's attribution
黄纸是在2014年创建的。这是更加限制的许可证。这是归因
share-like, which means if you use it, you have to release your stuff under the same license,
类似于股份，这意味着如果您使用它，则必须在同一许可证下释放您的东西，
which is pretty decent for specification, but a little bit annoying for code.
这对于规格来说很不错，但对于代码来说有点烦人。
Here, I'm going to give you a really, really fast tour of the yellow paper.
在这里，我将为您提供非常非常快速的黄纸之旅。
And the important thing here is I don't like the yellow paper, so I'm going to be a little
这里重要的是我不喜欢黄纸，所以我会有点
bit biased in my tour. So to any appreciators of the yellow paper out there, I want to apologize.
在我的巡回演出中有点偏见。因此，对于任何黄纸的欣赏者，我要道歉。
But let's get into that. So the yellow paper is mostly English text. It gives a lot of background, a lot of good rationale for why things are the way they are.
但是让我们开始。因此，黄纸主要是英文文字。它给出了很多背景，这是为什么事物是这样的理由。
It's also intermixed with very technical academic kind of notation here. So this snippet here is describing what a blockchain is.
这里还与非常技术性的学术符号相互混合。因此，此片段在这里描述了一个区块链。
So, formula one here is saying that the state at time plus one is equivalent to the state at time with the state, sorry, applying the state transition function to the state at time and a set of transactions.
因此，一级方程式在这里说的是，在时间时期的状态与国家相等，对不起，将状态过渡功能应用于时间和一组交易。
And then that might sound familiar to any people familiar with blockchains.
然后，对任何熟悉区块链的人来说，这听起来都可能很熟悉。
That's how they write it in the yellow paper.
这就是他们在黄纸上写的方式。
We also have a definition here of what proof of work is, and you can kind of see how all of that works.
我们在这里也有一个关于什么是工作证明的定义，您可以查看所有这些工作的工作原理。
We also go into what the fork choice rule is, and you kind of describe how clients choose which fork to follow.
我们还进入了叉子选择规则的内容，您可以描述客户如何选择遵循哪个叉子。
And here we have a definition of the state.
在这里，我们对国家有一个定义。
So this is probably one of my favorite examples of the yellow paper doing both an incredibly good job and an incredibly bad job at describing what the state is.
因此，这可能是我最喜欢的黄纸示例之一，既做出了令人难以置信的好工作，又是描述状态的糟糕工作。
So these English descriptions, they're amazing.
因此，这些英语描述，它们很棒。
They tell you what is in the state.
他们告诉你州的什么。
You got the nonce, balance, storage, root, code, hash, all things that you're going to be familiar with if you're working with the EVM.
如果您使用EVM，您将获得NONCE，平衡，存储，根，代码，哈希，所有您将熟悉的事物。
But on the right-hand side, we have these incredibly dense notations that explain how the tri is encoded, which is number eight here.
但是在右侧，我们有这些令人难以置信的密集符号，可以解释TRI的编码方式，这是第八位。
And you'll have how the contract's internal state, its key value pair mapping is encoded here.
您将拥有合同的内部状态，其钥匙值对映射在此处编码。
I don't know what those mean. I've implemented the Python version, and I still don't understand what these functions mean.
我不知道那是什么意思。我已经实现了Python版本，但我仍然不明白这些功能的含义。
So that's kind of why the inspiration for trying to replace the yellow paper.
这就是为什么尝试更换黄纸的灵感的原因。
Again, here's an example of what the transaction looks like.
同样，这是交易外观的一个示例。
So we have our English definitions here, and they're fairly understandable.
因此，我们在这里有我们的英语定义，它们相当可理解。
And then you have this lovely blob over here.
然后，您在这里有一个可爱的斑点。
it's so transaction is a tuple of tntp tg tttv p tw tr and ts and if anybody can remember what
如此交易是TNTP TG TG TTTV P TW和TS的元组，如果有人能记住什么
any of those variables mean you guys deserve a prize um i don't um again the block great
这些变量中的任何一个意味着你们应该获得奖品，我再也不会吧，街区很棒
description of all of the things that are in it um super useful if you're implementing a client
如果您正在实施客户
um and then you have the rest of the yellow paper gas the entire virtual machine how rlp works
嗯，然后您拥有其余的黄纸气，整个虚拟机RLP的工作原理
it's all defined in the yellow paper.
所有这些都在黄纸中定义。
It's a very dense document.
这是一个非常密集的文件。
Yeah.
是的。
Now all of these formulas here are
现在所有这些公式都是
examples from the previous slides,
以前幻灯片的示例，
and I've already forgotten what they mean,
而且我已经忘记了它们的意思，
so that's kind of the biggest problem.
这是最大的问题。
I think with yellow paper is that
我认为黄纸是
these notations, while they are very
这些符号，虽然它们非常
succinct, are very difficult to understand.
简洁，很难理解。
So why, like who's the yellow paper targeting?
那么，为什么，就像谁是黄纸靶向？
it's not targeting developers, and I think that's the biggest problem with it.
它不是针对开发人员，我认为这是最大的问题。
Programmers are the people who need to understand it the most, the people who are actually writing
程序员是最需要理解它的人，实际上正在写作的人
clients. And then the other people who are using the yellow paper are EIP authors. So if you're
客户。然后使用黄纸的其他人是EIP作者。所以，如果你是
trying to propose a change to Ethereum, you need to describe that change in some way.
试图提出对以太坊的更改，您需要以某种方式描述这种变化。
And none of these documents use the notation from the yellow paper. Half of any core EIP is
这些文档都没有使用黄纸中的符号。任何核心EIP的一半是
is defining a language to describe the change. Oftentimes it's Python. So, we wanted to give
正在定义一种描述变化的语言。通常是Python。所以，我们想给予
a more formal notation for that. The yellow paper is English, so it's not testable. There's no way
为此更正式的符号。黄纸是英语的，因此无法测试。没有办法
to write a test to make sure that a client conforms to the specification. And there's no way
编写测试以确保客户端符合规范。没有办法
to use the yellow paper to fill tests. But to be fair, and, you know, I don't want to just rag on
使用黄纸填充测试。但是公平地说，你知道，我不想只是抹布
on the yellow paper the whole time.
在黄纸上一直在黄纸上。
It's very succinct.
这很简洁。
So it's only a couple pages
所以只有几页
and it does a very good job
而且做得很好
of formally describing Ethereum
正式描述以太坊
if you understand that kind of notation.
如果您理解这种符号。
And I think the most important benefit
我认为最重要的好处
as far as I'm concerned
就我而言
is that the yellow paper
是黄纸
is algorithm independent.
是算法独立的。
It doesn't specify how things work,
它没有指定事物的工作方式，
only the observable behaviors of it.
只有它可观察到的行为。
And I think that's a really
我认为那真的是
underappreciated benefit
被低估的利益
of the yellow paper
黄纸
and something that we don't have
还有我们没有的东西
with ELs.
与Els。
On that note, EELS was created in 2021 by ConsenSys' Quilt team.
在这一点上，鳗鱼是由Consensys的被子团队于2021年创建的。
Maintainership has been moved to the EELS team at the Ethereum Foundation.
维护企业已移至以太坊基金会的鳗鱼团队。
We're under a more permissive license.
我们受到更宽松的许可。
We're basically public domain.
我们基本上是公共领域。
So, you know, kind of why did we start making EELS?
所以，你知道，为什么我们为什么开始制作鳗鱼？
We wanted to escape the frustration of trying to understand the yellow paper.
我们想摆脱试图理解黄纸的挫败感。
I've read it a dozen times.
我已经读了十几次。
I have a hard time understanding it still.
我仍然很难理解它。
And I'm not an expert developer, so I kind of think I'm a reasonable representation of most people working on Ethereum.
而且我不是专家开发人员，所以我认为我是大多数从事以太坊的人的合理代表。
There's also no snapshot of the current state of Ethereum.
当前的以太坊状态也没有快照。
So if you've ever read the yellow paper, you'll notice that it lags behind by a fork or two.
因此，如果您曾经阅读过黄纸，您会注意到它落在一两个叉子后面。
Right now it's only been updated until Paris, if I remember correctly.
现在，如果我没记错的话，它才被更新到巴黎。
So you have to take the Paris yellow paper, find all of the EIPs that have come out since then,
因此，您必须拿起巴黎黄纸，找到从那以后出现的所有EIP
and that is how you figure out what the current state of Ethereum is.
这就是您找出以太坊的当前状态的方式。
Which is a little difficult, and we wanted something that is more up-to-date
这有点困难，我们想要更新的东西
and provides kind of a snapshot of what Ethereum is right now.
并提供了现在以太坊的快照。
We want it to be more accessible to programmers.
我们希望程序员更容易访问它。
That's kind of like the number one goal, I guess.
我想这有点像第一目标。
Python is very readable.
Python非常可读。
The consensus layer specs were already written in Python.
共识层规格已经用Python编写。
So we wanted to do that for us, too.
因此，我们也想为我们做到这一点。
And then our final big, you know, motivation for doing this is to be able to fill the automated tests.
然后，我们知道这样做的动机是能够填写自动测试。
So Geth has been the reference client for a very, very long time.
因此，格斯（Geth）是很长一段时间以来一直是参考客户端。
And we wanted to kind of have a simpler client that isn't cluttered with complexities of a real client.
而且我们想拥有一个更简单的客户，它并不包含真实客户的复杂性。
And that's kind of what we wanted to do here.
这就是我们想在这里做的事情。
So now it's time to kind of give you a tour of EELS.
所以现在是时候让您参观鳗鱼了。
So I'm going to give you rough example or rough equivalent to the one I gave for the yellow paper.
因此，我将为您提供粗略的榜样，或者与我给黄纸的那一张相等的榜样。
The first thing I want to show is our directory structure.
我要显示的第一件事是我们的目录结构。
So we have a folder.
因此，我们有一个文件夹。
We have a bunch of utility stuff like integer types and implementation of ethash.
我们有很多实用程序，例如整数类型和Ethash的实现。
But most importantly, we have a folder for each fork.
但最重要的是，我们为每个叉子都有一个文件夹。
And each of these folders contains a complete copy of the Ethereum specification.
这些文件夹中的每一个都包含以太坊规范的完整副本。
If you were to take, say, just Paras and delete everything else, you would have a working implementation of the Paras hard fork.
例如，如果您要采取的措施并删除其他所有内容，那么您将有工作的硬叉实施。
And that's kind of one of the big differences between our client and, let's say, Geth or Nethermind, is that Paras stands alone.
这是我们客户之间的最大差异之一，可以说是Geth或Nethermind，就是Paras独自一人。
You can read the Paras folder and get a complete idea of what Paras is.
您可以阅读Paras文件夹，并了解什么是Paras。
So this is kind of like what the blockchain implementation looks like in ELSE compared
因此，这就像区块链实现的外观
to the ELO paper.
到Elo纸。
We have regular classes that define what each data structure we need is, and then we have
我们有定期的类，可以定义我们需要的每个数据结构，然后我们有
regular Python functions that define what the behavior is.
定义行为的常规python函数。
So you can see, very similar to Xiaowei's presentation about the consensus layer specs,
因此，您可以看到，与xiaowei关于共识层规格的演示非常相似，
We have our assertions that show what we check to make sure that the state transition was
我们有我们的断言显示了我们检查的内容，以确保国家过渡是
performed successfully.
成功。
We have Python functions that implement little chunks of the algorithms that we need.
我们拥有Python功能，可以实现我们需要的算法的小部分。
And then right here in 194, that's actually building the blockchain.
然后在194年，这实际上是在建造区块链。
So we try very hard to keep it very simple Python, very easy to understand.
因此，我们非常努力地保持非常简单的python，非常容易理解。
So similarly here is validating the proof of work for a particular block.
因此，这里类似地验证了特定块的工作证明。
it's not exactly fork choice, but it's what we have.
这不是分叉的选择，而是我们拥有的。
We don't, we expect to receive only the correct blocks
我们没有，我们希望只收到正确的块
because we don't handle reorgs.
因为我们不处理重复。
That would be a whole extra complication in our database
这将是我们数据库中的全部额外复杂性
that we don't touch.
我们不碰。
But we do have a full state implementation.
但是我们确实有一个国家实施。
So all of the things you expect an Ethereum state
因此，您期望以太坊的所有事物
to be able to do, we can do.
为了做到，我们可以做到。
And these are representations of our transactions.
这些都是我们交易的代表。
We try to have meaningful names for all of our classes and all of their values.
我们尝试为我们所有班级及其所有价值观都有有意义的名字。
Yeah.
是的。
And here's a block just for completeness sake.
这是一个仅出于完整的缘故。
It looks like a regular Python class.
看起来像是普通的Python课程。
So the downside to EELS.
因此，鳗鱼的缺点。
Obviously it requires Python knowledge.
显然，这需要Python知识。
It's written in Python.
它用python写。
If you want to contribute, you have to use Python.
如果您想贡献，则必须使用Python。
Whereas Yellow Paper does.
而黄纸则是。
It is English.
是英语。
so you can just write text and have people understand you.
因此，您可以写文字并让人们了解您。
We do require specific algorithm choices.
我们确实需要特定的算法选择。
So when the yellow paper can say, like, we expect X and Y to happen,
因此，当黄纸可以说，就像，我们希望X和Y发生时，
we have to actually write a particular implementation of what X and Y is.
我们必须实际编写x和y是什么的特定实现。
And that can leak into downstream implementations.
这可能会泄漏到下游实现。
And that's something we have to be very careful about.
这是我们必须非常小心的事情。
It's also more verbose.
这也是更多的详细信息。
We have easily an order of magnitude more code than there is text in the yellow paper.
与黄纸中的文本相比，我们的代码很容易多。
it's less accessible to people who are familiar with the yellow paper. On the other hand,
熟悉黄纸的人来说，它不太容易进入。另一方面，
the benefits of ELLs are it's super easy to identify these things. These signatures and
ELL的好处是识别这些东西非常容易。这些签名和
class definitions are very understandable to anybody who can read Python. You know that
对于任何可以阅读Python的人来说，班级定义都是非常可理解的。你知道
the first one here is the state transition function. There's no tuple of T, subscript
这里的第一个是状态过渡函数。没有元组，下标
it's all very understandable.
这都是可以理解的。
Understandable programmers, which is important.
可以理解的程序员，这很重要。
And we already match what people do in EIPs.
我们已经匹配了人们在EIP中所做的事情。
You can use actual Python.
您可以使用实际的Python。
We're also more well maintained.
我们也更加维护。
The three of us work full time.
我们三个人全职工作。
Well, two of us work full time, and I work most of my time on this.
好吧，我们两个人全职工作，我大部分时间都在工作。
And it's very easy for anybody to contribute.
任何人都很容易做出贡献。
We have people coming in and making drive-by pull requests pretty much all the time.
我们几乎一直都在进来并提出开车请求。
And we're implemented all the way up to Cancun.
我们一直实施到坎昆。
So this is something I'm really excited about.
所以这是我真的很兴奋的事情。
And if I'm talking too fast, I have to apologize.
如果我说的太快，我必须道歉。
But we can sync the chain.
但是我们可以同步链。
So you can take EELS, you can put it on a very, very powerful computer, and it will eventually sync mainnet.
因此，您可以服用鳗鱼，可以将其放在非常非常强大的计算机上，并最终将同步主网。
And that's something I think we're pretty proud of.
这就是我认为我们非常自豪的事情。
It also passes the Ethereum test suite.
它还通过以太坊测试套件。
So, every test that normal execution clients pass, we also pass those as well.
因此，每个正常执行客户端都通过的测试，我们也通过这些测试。
And we can do the opposite.
我们可以做相反的事情。
So, you can write, you can prototype your EIP in ELSE and use ELSE to generate tests
因此，您可以写作，您可以在其他地方原型原型，并使用其他来生成测试
for other clients.
对于其他客户。
Some other cool things that I think would be interesting to talk about that we've been
我认为我们已经去过的其他一些很酷的事情会很有趣
working on.
继续工作。
So, diffs.
因此，差异。
This is, you know, my baby.
这是我的孩子。
been working on this for a while. Because each hard fork is a complete implementation of the
已经为此工作了一段时间。因为每个硬叉都是完整的实现
Ethereum protocol it's very hard to tell the difference between like to see what's changed.
以太坊协议很难说出要看发生了什么变化之间的区别。
So this one here is an example of the DAO fork. We've written custom documentation tooling to
因此，这是DAO叉的一个例子。我们已经写了自定义文档工具
generate these diffs and you can see them on our website which will be linked at the end.
生成这些差异，您可以在我们的网站上看到它们，该网站将在最后链接。
What else? We also participate in fuzzing. So this is a very recent feature.
还有什么？我们还参加模糊。因此，这是一个最近的功能。
I think as of last week, we got this in.
我认为截至上周，我们得到了。
So all of the current execution clients participate in fuzzing
因此，所有当前的执行客户都参与模糊
where random inputs are assembled and thrown at the client
组装随机输入并向客户端扔的地方
to see what happens.
看看会发生什么。
We participate in that now.
我们现在参与其中。
So yeah, I think that's pretty neat.
是的，我认为这很整洁。
And it's already found a few bugs in our implementation
它已经在我们的实施中找到了一些错误
and a few bugs in other clients.
以及其他客户中的一些错误。
So yeah, that's about it for the formal presentation here.
是的，这就是这里的正式演讲。
So I will stop at this point, take some questions, and then if there's still time at the end, I can do a demo of adding some stuff to ELs if people are interested.
因此，我将在这一点上停下来，提出一些问题，然后，如果还有时间结束时，如果人们有兴趣，我可以做一些演示，以向EL添加一些东西。
Awesome. Thank you so much, Sam. Yeah, it was great. I appreciate it. Thank you very much.
惊人的。非常感谢，山姆。是的，太好了。我很感激。非常感谢。
Folks, if you have any questions, feel free to ask right now. It's the best time.
伙计们，如果您有任何疑问，请立即提出询问。这是最好的时光。
Meanwhile, I wanted to say that I'm very surprised that you synced the chain.
同时，我想说的是，我对您同步链条感到非常惊讶。
I didn't know about that.
我不知道。
It's super cool.
太酷了。
How long does it take?
多久时间？
So we don't run it regularly.
因此，我们不会定期运行它。
So I think the last time we synced it was two or three months ago,
因此，我认为我们上次同步是两个或三个月前
and it took two weeks or so.
这花了两个星期左右。
It's very slow.
非常慢。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
And once you get up to recent blocks,
一旦到达最近的块，
it's like a block comes out every 12 seconds,
就像一个街区每12秒出来一次，
and we complete a block every 10 seconds.
我们每10秒完成一次街区。
So it's, yeah, very hard to catch up,
是的，很难赶上
but we can sync the chain.
但是我们可以同步链。
That's amazing.
太神奇了。
I mean, I didn't expect it that Python would be,
我的意思是，我没想到Python会，
Python client would be able to sync
Python客户将能够同步
like the later, the modern Ethereum.
像后来的现代以太坊一样。
I remember Trinity trying to do it years ago.
我记得三位一体试图在几年前尝试这样做。
I think they never managed to sync, so.
我认为他们从来没有设法同步。
Yeah, so there are some caveats here.
是的，所以这里有一些警告。
we have a 128 gig RAM computer with very powerful processors. It's not an easy task. I wouldn't
我们有一台具有非常强大的处理器的128 GIG RAM计算机。这不是一件容易的事。我不会
recommend anybody doing it, but it's possible. Awesome, awesome. Yeah, one question here.
推荐任何人这样做，但这是可能的。很棒，很棒。是的，这里一个问题。
You mentioned that the ELs are up to date with Cancun, but in the repo, we just see Shanghai.
您提到ELS与Cancun是最新的，但是在回购中，我们只是看到上海。
So where can we find the specs post?
那么我们在哪里可以找到规格帖子？
Yeah, so there is a fork, a branch fork slash Cancun.
是的，所以有一个叉子，一个分支叉斜线cancun。
We just haven't merged it into master yet.
我们只是还没有将其合并为主人。
There's a few refactoring things you want to take care of, but it's all there.
您想照顾一些重构的事情，但这一切都在那里。
Okay, cool.
好吧，很酷。
So it's the branch.
所以这是分支。
Yeah, and also you mentioned that, so there are things which are omitted from, which are missing
是的，而且您也提到了，所以有些东西忽略了，缺少
from the exec fields, like the peer-to-peer or the fork choice. Can you maybe mention where you can
从执行字段（例如点对点或叉子选择）中。你可以提到你可以的地方吗
find specification for these? I guess they're the execution API specs as well?
找到这些规格？我想它们也是执行API规格吗？
Yeah, so the APIs are, like you said, in the execution APIs. There's the networking
是的，就像您说的那样，API在执行API中。有网络
specification. I don't have it link candy for it, but it's under the Ethereum repository as well.
规格。我没有它链接糖果，但它也在以太坊存储库下。
And for the fork choice, we're just going to be adding English text describing how that works.
对于叉子的选择，我们将添加英文文本描述其工作原理。
It adds a lot of complexity being able to do rollbacks and switching between forks,
它增加了很多复杂性，能够进行回滚并在叉之间切换，
and that's not something that we can really reasonably handle. Yeah.
这不是我们真正可以合理地处理的事情。是的。
Thank you so much. Any other questions, folks?
太感谢了。还有其他问题，伙计们吗？
Actually, there's something I forgot to mention. So the consensus layer specs took the approach
实际上，我忘了提到一些东西。因此，共识层规格采用了该方法
of starting in Markdown and rendering to Python, and we took the exact opposite approach. So
从Markdown开始并渲染Python，我们采取了完全相反的方法。所以
start in Python and render it into HTML.
从Python开始，然后将其呈现为HTML。
So it's kind of a very opposite approach.
因此，这是一种非常相反的方法。
We have a Python-first thing, and they have a Markdown-first.
我们有第一件事，他们有一个降价优先。
And, you know, we both end up with, I think,
而且，你知道，我俩都遇到了
reasonable documents at the end.
最后的文件。
It's just an interesting fact.
这只是一个有趣的事实。
Okay, awesome, awesome.
好吧，很棒，很棒。
Yeah, it's an interesting comparison.
是的，这是一个有趣的比较。
Okay.
好的。
I would repeat the question that you asked,
我会重复您问的问题，
what was the most challenging
最具挑战性的是什么
that you find? I mean, you mentioned
你发现吗？我的意思是，你提到
issues with creating yellow paper and so on.
制作黄纸等问题。
What do you find
你发现了什么
the biggest challenge of it?
最大的挑战？
So,
所以，
kind of a similar problem.
有点类似的问题。
Writing Ethereum,
写以太坊，
the actual Python for it,
实际的python，
isn't the hardest part of this project it's all of the associated tooling being able to render
不是这个项目中最难的部分，是所有相关的工具能够渲染
everything um we had to build a whole new rendering system a whole new documentation tool
我们必须建立一个全新的渲染系统，这是一个全新的文档工具
um that that's been the hardest part it's just making it presentable to people and accessible
嗯，那是最困难的部分，它只是使人们可以呈现给人们
yeah it's it's been also a while like before you started it actually the specs was there but uh
是的，这也已经有一段时间了，就像您启动之前，规格在那里，但是
it got officially announced as the released version which is presentable, it took a while
它被正式宣布为发布的版本，花了一段时间
because it didn't work.
因为它不起作用。
So yeah.
是的。
Okay, um...
好吧，嗯...
Let's...
让我们...
Yeah, I think we can wrap up. There are just a few questions we can answer later.
是的，我认为我们可以总结。我们稍后可以回答一些问题。
And we are at almost the hour, so yeah, if you have anything else you would like to elaborate
而且我们几乎是一个小时，是的，如果您有其他任何您想详细说明的
on, show us, also share the screen, and show us some of the repo or some more hands-on
在上面，向我们展示，也共享屏幕，并向我们展示一些回购或更多动手
coding example or it would be very thankful.
编码示例，否则将非常感谢。
Yeah, it can definitely do that.
是的，绝对可以做到这一点。
So, just find the right window here.
因此，只需在这里找到正确的窗口即可。
There we go.
我们去。
So this is kind of an unrehearsed live demo
所以这是一个未经训练的现场演示
of adding an Opcode to EALS.
将OpCode添加到EALS中。
So we're going to start off by just,
因此，我们将首先
let me just move this over here a little bit there.
让我将其移到这里。
So you can get ELs.
这样您就可以得到EL。
So we're starting from scratch.
因此，我们从头开始。
We're cloning the ELs repository and we're going to go right into that.
我们正在克隆ELS存储库，我们将继续进行。
So now we have the execution specs repository and we have to set up our virtual environment,
因此，现在我们拥有执行规范存储库，我们必须设置虚拟环境，
which is the second step.
这是第二步。
So virtual environments, if you're not familiar with Python, are like a local package repository
因此，如果您不熟悉Python，虚拟环境就像本地软件包存储库
so you don't mess up your system Python.
因此，您不会弄乱系统python。
So let's turn that on.
因此，让我们打开它。
There we go.
我们去。
So now we're in our virtual environment, and you can see that our Python is also sandboxed
因此，现在我们处于虚拟环境中，您可以看到我们的python也是沙盒
inside the virtual environment.
在虚拟环境中。
So let's add an opcode.
因此，让我们添加一个操作码。
My favorite up go to add is increment, pop a number off the stack and push one greater
我最喜欢的添加是增量，从堆栈中弹出一个数字，然后推高一个
than that number back onto the stack.
比该数字回到堆栈中。
Let's do that.
让我们这样做。
First step here is installing the project so that we can edit it.
这里的第一步是安装项目，以便我们可以对其进行编辑。
We use pip as our package management system.
我们将PIP用作包装管理系统。
Should be pretty familiar to any Python developers.
任何Python开发人员都应该非常熟悉。
you're not a Python developer, all you need to know is pip install dash e dot. There we go.
您不是Python开发人员，您需要知道的只是PIP安装仪表板E点。我们去。
So that's installed all of our dependencies, gotten everything set up. We actually depend
因此，这已经安装了我们所有的依赖关系，并设置了所有设置。我们实际上依赖
on the execution specs as well for their implementation of, I think it's kzg commitments.
关于执行规格，我认为这是KZG的承诺。
So yeah, we already share a bunch of code. So let's go and check out the Cancun branch,
是的，我们已经共享了一堆代码。因此，让我们去检查坎昆分支，
because that one's a fun one to start from.
因为那是一个有趣的开始。
So this is going to be an arithmetic instruction. So everything to do with the EVM lives under the
因此，这将是算术指令。因此，与EVM生活有关的一切
VM folder. Hopefully that's an obvious choice. So this is what, let me resize this a second, perfect.
VM文件夹。希望这是一个明显的选择。这就是什么，让我调整一个完美的大小。
So here's the add opcode. This is the implementation. Every opcode is divided into the same four sections. We have stack manipulation, charging gas, the actual implementation of the opcode, and then incrementing or not incrementing the program counter.
因此，这是添加opcode。这是实现。每个操作码分为相同的四个部分。我们进行了堆栈操作，充电气体，OpCode的实际实施，然后增加或不增加程序计数器。
So let's copy the add instruction here and change it to ink.
因此，让我们在此处复制添加说明并将其更改为墨水。
So let's delete the doc string here.
因此，让我们在此处删除DOC字符串。
There we go.
我们去。
So we're only going to pop one item off the stack, which is going to be the input number.
因此，我们只会从堆栈中弹出一个项目，这将是输入号码。
We're going to charge the same amount of gas, which will be gas very low.
我们将充电相同数量的气体，这将是非常低的气体。
and we will add 1 to the value we popped off the stack,
我们将在我们从堆栈中弹出的价值添加1个，
and we will push it back onto the stack here.
我们将把它推回这里的堆栈。
This only takes one byte to encode,
这只需要一个字节来编码，
so we'll leave the program counter at plus 1.
因此，我们将在Plus 1离开程序计数器。
Now, we have to actually tell the interpreter about our new opcode,
现在，我们实际上必须告诉解释器有关我们的新操作码，
so let's go and do that.
所以让我们去做吧。
That is in the init folder.
那就是在初始文件夹中。
So let's give it 0C as the numeric representation of it.
因此，让我们将其作为数字表示。
So we have to add it to this enumeration of instructions here.
因此，我们必须在此处将其添加到此指令中。
And then we can go down and add it, add the implementation.
然后我们可以下降并添加它，添加实现。
Yeah, which would be right here.
是的，这将就在这里。
So instead of ops sign extend, we have ops ink.
因此，我们有OPS墨水而不是OPS符号扩展。
And then we will have the ink instruction.
然后我们将拥有墨水指令。
And that is the entirety of adding a new opcode to EELS.
这就是向鳗鱼添加新的opode的完整。
It is really a very simple Python program.
这确实是一个非常简单的Python程序。
There's no kind of weirdness to it.
没有什么怪异的。
There's no performance considerations.
没有绩效考虑。
Our version of the Cancun fork now has the increment instruction, and that's it.
我们的Cancun Fork版本现在具有增量指令，仅此而已。
Yeah, so that's pretty much the demo.
是的，这几乎就是演示。
If you ever have any questions or want to work on this stuff, please reach out to me.
如果您有任何疑问或想处理这些事情，请与我联系。
I'm pretty available on Discord, Twitter, whatever you like.
无论您喜欢什么，我都可以在Discord，Twitter上使用。
Thanks so much for letting me demo that.
非常感谢您让我演示。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Thanks so much, Sam, for doing the demo.
非常感谢Sam进行演示。
So much for doing the demo.
进行演示非常重要。
Thank you so much, Sam, for doing this.
非常感谢您，Sam这样做。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Yeah, I appreciate it that you are
是的，我感谢你是
able to just come and do the live session
能够来进行现场会议
and show us code in ELs.
并在EL中向我们展示代码。
It's pretty cool.
很酷。
And folks can try it themselves for the recording, I guess.
我想人们可以自己尝试录音。
Awesome.
惊人的。
There was one question from Pooja here
Pooja这里有一个问题
I wanted to ask as an EIP ELs person, before the ERC split, there was talk about proposing EIPs with ELs.
我想作为EIP ELS人问，在ERC分裂之前，有关于与ELS提出EIP的讨论。
Do we see that in the near future?
我们在不久的将来看到吗？
That's a question that's kind of up in the air.
这是一个空中的问题。
So you can link to ELs from EIPs.
因此，您可以链接到EIPS的EL。
So if you want to use code you've written in ELs in your document, you can.
因此，如果您想使用文档中的EL中编写的代码，则可以。
But the original vision of moving core EIPs into this repository is kind of dead.
但是将核心EIP转移到该存储库的最初愿景已经死了。
So think of ELs more as one of the many ways to express your change and not the only way to express your change.
因此，更多地将EL视为表达您的变化的众多方法之一，而不是表达您的变化的唯一方法。
it's pretty cool um yeah
很酷嗯
okay i think i think we can wrap up um it's been it's been over an hour and we borrowed
好吧，我想我想我们可以总结一下，嗯，已经超过一个小时了，我们借了
a lot today so uh yeah thank you so much again sam xiaowei if you're still here and sitting
今天很多，嗯，是的
yous to both of you uh huge thanks for uh demonstrating and explaining the uh both
你们俩都非常感谢您演示和解释UH
sides of the specs uh so yeah um and thanks so much for all your all your hard work on the
规格的一面是的，是的，非常感谢您在
specs themselves like uh we have properly specified it here finally and it's it's there
像嗯一样，我们已经在这里正确地指定了它，最终它在那里
So it's it's really amazing to do that.
因此，这样做真是太神奇了。
So thank you all so much.
所以非常感谢大家。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Great. Yeah.
伟大的。是的。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Thanks, Sam and Syawei.
谢谢Sam和Syawei。
And we will see you all
我们会见大家
in a couple of days for the first session
在第一次会议的几天内
with the research track, I believe it is
有了研究轨道，我相信这是
on starting with
从开始
Denkrad.
丹克拉德。
It's
它是
Denkrad Inc. with Denkrad himself
Denkrad Inc.与Denkrad本人
on Wednesday, 4pm.
周三下午4点。
So we'll continue to week 6
所以我们将继续第6周
with the research track there.
那里的研究轨道。
And yeah, guys, you've been the
是的，伙计们，你一直是
first to give a talk in our
首先在我们的
development track, so we really appreciate it
开发轨道，所以我们真的很感激
for empowering the future
赋予未来能力
Ethereum developers.
以太坊开发人员。
And also, like, the
还有，就像
current ones, I believe, many people can learn
我相信，目前的人可以学习
from the talk there, so
从那里的演讲，所以
it will be appreciated yeah yeah it's much and we'll see you Wednesday and
是的，这将不胜感激，这是很多，我们将在星期三见到您
it's me
这就是我
thanks everyone
谢谢大家
Thank you.
谢谢。